Hello and welcome back to Python, core and applied concepts for reliable data sense workflow.
Today we will start a new module which is module 5 and this module will be mostly about
functions and they are using Python programming language.
So functions as another programming construct is a very important idea in any programming
language and it helps your whole core structure to keep very clean and structure so that any
future development can be benefited from this clean structure and its reusability perspective.
So we will talk about this in detail today how to create functions, how to use them,
what are some common pitfalls that you may encounter if you don't look at the function
arguments carefully. So all of that but first just start with no question that when do we
really know that we need to write a function. So functions normally you write functions to
organize your code you don't always want your single function or the main function to be
very big monolithic piece of code. So if you figure out that some piece of code is being repeated
again and again then that's kind of a good sign to isolate that block of code and make it a little
more abstract general in the sense that it can be used in multiple ways at multiple places.
So that's kind of a hint that you get when you see this kind of repetitive code.
That's what I'm going to discuss here. The three pillars of function utility is what we want to see.
So these three kind of behavior or these three kind of pattern will help you figure out whether you
should write a function for this particular piece of code or not. So the very first thing is no
reusability. So you write a function only once and then you can use it everywhere. So if you feel
that let's say a sequence of instructions which you have written for your current program can be
used at other places also maybe to solve some other problem in some other context.
Then and if you think this will repeat multiple times then it's a good idea to abstract out that
four line or five line of code into a separate function that you can call at any point and then
use it rather than writing those four line of code everywhere whenever it appears. So this is
very first sign when you would probably know that this is the best time to write a function instead
of writing this four line of instructions for not achieving this particular objective.
So reusability is the very first pillar or first observation that you can make when you know
that you now need to write a function. So the main idea is that you write no only once and use
it everywhere. So when you find yourself copying and pasting the same logic in multiple places
you have identified a perfect candidate for a function. So this is what we want to say
and function can in encapsulate common operations along you to debug and test them no ones
then deploy them anywhere. So this is also an advantage right if you isolate this four piece of
code at one place in in form of function you can maybe put all your effort to write it correctly
only once and then whenever you deploy it knowing any context and you can safely rely that these
four line of code actually does the job that it is intended to do. So this is not only
development time but also ensures somehow consistency right if you need to fix a bug or improve the
logic you only have to do it in one place. Later on if you find figure out let's say that this
four piece of you know four line of code can be improved and maybe made more can we make can we
made more efficient. So what you need to do is to just know look at that function and just
improve its no performance instead of you know going to every place where you have maybe return
the function or this four line of code and replacing those four line of code not each of these
places okay. So this is you know one example and here you can see I have given some you know
examples I mean like I mean if you want to let's calculate the area of room. So you can one
thing I mean you can do is you can always let's say you know multiplies no dimension and then
get the area for example if you want to no calculate area of room one followed by room two
then room three. So you can write down this kind of code this is perfectly you know all right I
mean it will give you the desired result but then this is not the most or it's not the best way
to do this kind of job rather than it I mean we can maybe define some function which actually
calculates the area and you just pass the argument to the function and get the final result.
So area may be you know very simple you know very primitive simple example which might not highlight
the essence of what I wanted to say but you know I hope you get the point that I mean if you have
a come even complicated no piece of what let's say multiple line of code which you think can be
used at multiple places it's best to you know write down them in form of a function and then use
call function at all those places where you know these things are needed okay. So some other
example like material cost or printing cost if you want to calculate always and it's better to write
down functions instead of you know doing those things look at you can write down these no sequence
of instructions to perform them again and again here although I mean there's no one instruction
computes what you desire so it may may not be the best you know candidate for function but then
I mean in general we want or we would like to convert our no code structure in this form of a
modular structure where mostly we use functions no for whatever task we want to get it done okay.
So this is the first no thing that comes I mean this is the first kind of no pattern that appears
when we feel that we should write function okay. The second kind of thing is the complexity of the
problem if the problem that you're solving is very let's say complex okay and you can solve that
problem by writing you know a large piece of code but then that's not a good idea right because
thinking about the whole logic in one go may be very difficult right and in computer science this
is a very common practice that when you encounter difficult problem normally we used this concept
of divide and conquer right we try to think I mean what if I can solve you know multiple simple
problems can I combine in some way the solution of those simple problems to solve my bigger problem.
So this is no called divide and conquer and I would know argue that the success of computer science
heavily realized on these kind of principles where you can think decompose the main problem into
you know simpler problem and try to solve those simpler problem first and then combine the solutions
of those simpler problem in a meaningful way to get the solution of no the bigger problem.
Remember this is not you know thumb roll or this is not something that will work all the time I
mean your your problems should have that kind of property so that you can decompose it you know
in smaller problem and it's not always possible but whenever it is possible I mean the suggestion is
you better decompose the problem into smaller problem and then try to solve those smaller problem
and then combine the solution to get the solution for the bigger problem and when you do this
you are essentially actually writing down again no simple functions to solve like study simple
problems so when you have all these functions ready which solves these you know various simple
problems what you can do is you can know call those functions one after another or you know combine
them in a meaningful way to get the solution of a bigger problem okay so this is very you know
useful technique that we again I mean always use in computer science complex problem becomes
very you know unmanageable I mean when you don't break it so it's better to break them you know in a
smaller you know focused pieces right which you can put your all energy to solve them right I mean
if you have multiple smaller problem and you're solving them one at a time you can devote all your
attention and energy into that smaller piece of you know writing in that smaller piece of code
and getting it correct now each function should have a single clear responsibility so when we
when we divide you know this problem into smaller problem we we know for sure that you know this
particular smaller problem will be solved by this function because it it somehow aligns with the
you know intention of the problem okay with the every no module or every every function that you
write has a very clear responsibility this approach makes code easier to understand also man you
can again I mean test them independently and also maintain it properly right so so all these you know
you know important feature of software development like you know testing or maintainability becomes
far more easier when you decompose the bigger problem into smaller problem and try to solve them
think of it like you know organizing a large project into a specialized teams where each team
you know handles one aspect of the problem okay so this you know conquer complexity through division is
a very you know useful tool it you know you can replace tangled you know monolithic dependency with
clean focused module that each you know will solve a specific part of the problem okay and when
you decompose things then at that moment of time it's very you know important to keep in mind that
how these you know different functions will interact with each other so they they should have
you know very clear established interface or you know boundary so you have to create stable
interfaces between components or to minimize coupling and maximize cohesion so so that I mean
they can be used you know the result of one can be used very easily by others so this is also what
you need to you know define properly so when you define the subproblems properly it becomes natural
to you know define these boundaries very clearly for the function that you know tries to solve those
subproblem okay another advantage know that you automatically get is that you can enable pedal
development right when you have isolated all these smaller problems now you can put you know multiple
teams to work simultaneously on these different you know modules are the different no problem that
you want to solve without you know integration complex so let's say I mean if you could divide
successfully and if you could establish this you know clear boundaries and you know interfaces
that will help them talk to each other without knowing the details of how the implementation has been
done then you can actually you know give these tasks to multiple teams and ask them to work simultaneously
on different models without no bothering about what will happen when I integrate the whole thing
into a single or enough project so so this again I mean that they're what I mean trying to use or
know making up you know having a practice of using functions as often as possible is or will also
reduce your time of development right because you can actually really get different tasks for
different people and what I said in the very beginning that you you can actually modify only
this piece of code and reuse it at multiple places is also an advantage that you can modify the
place or a scale individual component without destabilizing the entire system right in future if you
feel that you know some of the component my you know can be let's say improved for efficiency or
reliability or whatever you can actually safely do that without you know hindering the other
component right so this is this is what we are calling here you know evolutionary design you know
it supports actually evolutionary design where you figure out no at all at rest is that something
might be enhanced in in some some way okay and also I mean when you divide the whole problem and
we are when you are solving each of this problem the chances of localizing error is also
right here if some failure occurs let's say so you can actually localize the failure was caused
due to which of the component so that also becomes you know possible so all of these are actually
advantage and somehow you know can be categorized under this decomposition aspect of coming up with
the function okay so this is again I mean that I as I said hint to you I whenever you get some
complex problems just think about dividing it into simpler problems and then solving them for
example I mean one thing that we know almost know we know as a faculty member here always come up
with know this grading I mean although grading is not such a complex you know problem but still
we would like to if I have to know grade at the end of semester I would know think of this grading
activity as multiple you know sub problems which if I can achieve each I can maybe you know give
proper later grade to students so finally what we have to produce is a proper no later grade to
students but then before that we have to do a lot of activity right we have to you know evaluate
all the assignments you know everything and then we have to calculate weighted average of all these
things and then get the final later grade okay and you know many of these things are you know
changing throughout the semester so I mean if we keep track of these things separately and then
try to define them in form of know this modular structure of function or something like function then
it becomes very easy for us to you know produce later grade at the end of the semester okay
so this is one example that immediately came into my mind it is no not that complex but you can
imagine the hardest problem that you might have solved in your life and then try to look back
again go back to that problem and think back and see whether you can divide that problem into
smaller you know piece of code or a smaller you know sub problems that you can solve using
you know independent functions okay so this is you know one advantage another thing is know
this idea of abstraction so you know this this abstraction is a very no again I mean as
important idea as divided conquer in computer science because it helps you get rid of
the details which may not matter for the no bigger picture or the bigger you know system
of software to work so abstraction is no this idea where you can you know consider each of
these components which we are saying you know individual functions as a black box okay so
if you can consider them as a black box and if you know exactly how this you know black box behaves
while not knowing how these black box have been you know implemented then that gives
you added advantage right you can build on top of these functions very easily right if someone
has you know written nice reliable functions by describing properly what the function does
any third party can use those functions right we we're just looking at the you know description
of the function instead of the you know actual implementation of the function and we need not
worry about how it is implemented and this gives us tremendous you know strength in coming up
or solving bigger and complex problem because we don't now don't need to know deal with all the
no trivial details of every function implementation okay so but I mean for this kind of you know
abstraction to work perfectly you have to make the contract very clear right function has to
very clearly what it you know expects as input and what it will give as our output okay and
all the implementation details has to be hidden I mean if you can hide the implementation details
know well then there is nothing like it I mean then you have written or use the functions
you know strength in proper way and you know if if this is there then I mean it enables of course
collaboration among the team right so this separation imposed by clear contracts allows
you know different team members to work on separate modules efficiently relying on each
other's interfaces without understanding the no underlying detail okay so this this abstraction is
you know very very important I mean if you can abstract out all the detail and almost of the
detail in you know form of clear interface like you know this let's say I mean if some third
party or user want to use your you know function what he should be bothered about is only you know
what are the expected input and what is the you know output and a clear description of this not
the actual you know implementation so he should not be bothered with the implementation and if he
is not bothered with the implementation then he can quickly build on top your of your you know
function by using your function some nice project which is interested in you know solving this
or building very quickly okay this is also very important so function now you see I mean gives you
all these you know advantages which in some sense has used you know help computer science
lot I mean in you know past decades to you know in the development of systems and software okay
so that's why functions are you know so important so now let's now get to the minute details one
by one slowly so now let me go to this Jupiter notebook and so now let's start seeing
the actual implementation of function right I mean how to we have seen so many functions still
now in our discussion without you know explicitly are talking about how to define them you know
but now in today's lecture we will see how a function how how you can actually define a function
and then how you can call a function and how to pass you know parameters to a function in an
actual function called so let's start with a very you know basic which is the syntax okay syntax
of a function like any other construct we will first know we learn how to write a correct
function which is you know correct by syntax okay so this is the typical syntax of a function
that you can see here so let me increase the font a bit
okay so this is how the functions in text looks so we we write def for to indicate again I'm
comp python that we are going to define a function and followed by that we give a function name
here I have written you know function name but you can write down you know any valid identifier as
a function name here and then you can pass parameters to the function so parameters are like
argument so what will be the input to the function so this is what I was calling interface okay so
so inputs are also you know interface you know clear defining clearly what do you expect
as an argument for this function is very important and if you can clearly define that then
anyone can use it by just providing you know these no parameters as argument when calling this
function so these are parameters which you are defining you know inside this parenthesis which
you write just up to the function name and then this colon you know indicates that now you are
going to define the actual body of the function okay so it's a very good practice to write the
description of the function in the very beginning so what you see you know here as you know inside
this no quotation is a doc string okay so for you for your function to be reusable by any third
party you should try to write down the description of the function as clearly as you know possible
we will come to it again in the maybe next video and tell you some you know template you can use
to define you know the interface and working of your functions properly in the very beginning
itself okay so let's say someone else who doesn't know or have access to the source code of your
you know function and he still you know wants to know about how to use your function okay the way
I mean you know you try to get information about any let's say built-in or a standard library
function of Python is what someone wants to do with your function also you have written so if you
don't provide you know good doc string then he will not be able to get the details of your function
he has no other way but to know open up your function and see the implementation to figure out
what each argument means but the the doc string provides you a method or you know a way to describe
the behavior or the interface of your function using natural language like English okay so whatever
you write in this doc string can be accessed later on by any you know third party or user by using
just help function okay if he writes no help and then your function name this doc string will be printed
okay and this doc string I mean if you have written it properly user can know exactly by reading
this doc string what your function does okay so it can have a very nice natural language description
what is expected as input for your function and what your function calculates and what is the
you know format of output that you want to you know give or return from your function so all
this you can describe using you know English language in this doc string personnel okay so to
remember the doc string is the very you know in the beginning so just after the colon you start
this quotation mark and you write whatever you feel can be important for any you know third party
user when it he's using your function okay you can also mention I mean whether your function is
changing you know some argument which has been passed to it or not so this is called no generally
side effects so again we'll come back to it but just to mention that this is a important aspect
of writing a reusable function if you don't write doc string properly then your functions are
actually not reusable no no other person except you can maybe you know reuse it conveniently so it's
very important point and just keep in mind whenever you're writing a function spend some time
writing the doc string for your function then comes so you also this definition we have talked
about function name you talked about parameters and this doc string we know also talked about this
optional but no I would you know encourage to write doc string for every function that you know you
want to write you know for your purpose and if you think I mean you want it to be you reuse by
someone else then certainly try to write doc string then comes the function body say then whatever
you write you know after that and before return is the actual function body which will not do
the computation that you wanted to do for example in this case let's say we just wanted to know
some these two parameters and result that value so this is no simple you know statement which
implements this no intention okay so this is the function body or the actual code
for which we have written this function and then there is a return statement followed by
whatever you want to return I mean we'll see that we can return you know multiple things from inside
a function okay we may not want to return something you know explicitly like the way we have
done here and all of those you know variation we will not see as we go but this is more or less
the you know basic syntax of no function there are many variations possible and we will
no discuss them one by one so so just just to give you a practical example for example let's say
if you want to calculate total price of you know a number of objects let's say so I can actually
write down that code you know outside function also but I if you write it inside a function is
some much more in a modular style of coding so so for if you want to calculate the total price of
a let's say a number of you know pieces of certain type then what you need to pass it the quantity
and the unit price right if you pass quantity and unit price you can you know easily calculate
the total price right total so this is how you can maybe define a simple answers to to do job like
this okay where you define this calculate total price as the function name and pass two arguments
which which is any way necessary to calculate these things right so the quantity is the first
thing that you pass and then the unit price is the second thing so what is the price for every unit
and then inside the function you actually calculate the total you don't price to be quantity
multiplied by unit price and then you can return this total now whenever you want to you know
calculate total price you can simply call this function with this argument and this will return
you the value that you want it okay so you know something along the same line I mean another
function you can go through it in an offline mode but let me go ahead with now function calls okay
so what we have done so far is just define the function so defining the function does not
automatically mean that this function you know will be executed now it's like you know it's like
you know just defining the structure of the function or how this function will work when it is called
okay but if you don't call it then I mean there is no state change you know in the actual machine
or abstract machine that you are running okay this is just definition it gives the template
of set of actions or sequence of actions that will be executed when you call this function so
the important thing is that you you have to call this function to you know get this piece of code
executed so how to you know call functions so calling functions executed code with a specific
value the formal parameter in the definition becomes argument in the call okay so what we call
here is the you know as parameters you remember I mean these whatever you pass here inside this
function is called parameters so when you want this function to you know execute you have to call
this function with these parameters and when we call the function with this parameter we say that
we are passing argument you know which should be you know taken you know as you know value for this
parameter and then this function is to be done now when trying to you know call a function there
are multiple ways in which you can call a function so let me try to write some simple function and
then talk about these things in in that context so so there are multiple ways in which you can
actually pass this parameter values to the function so the very first way and the most you know used
this positional argument where you just pass the values for those you know parameter in the order
in which they were defined in the actual function okay so so for example let me define a very simple
function just for this purpose only so let's see a simple function like this which creates
a rectangle okay so creating a rectangle means I mean just no printing this that it has created
a rectangle with some you know area and some color okay so so if you pass you know length width
and color as an argument so let's say I mean if you want to create a rectangle with length 10
you know width 5 and color red then you will pass those three things as this
argument with a function and function will automatically take this value and then create or print
this statement for you which you know somehow you know is like simulating a creation of this rectangle
for you okay now how to call this you know function so so let's say this function is defined let me
run this piece of code okay so now since this function is defined what we want to do is we want to
call this function okay how to execute this function unless there's some parameters that we want
so the you know easiest way is to give the or the pass the parameters in order in which it has been
defined let's say the first thing that it expects is length okay so let me create some rectangle
for this so what we are trying to look at right now here this concept of
positional argument okay and in positional argument we will see that in the orders matter
okay so what does it mean that if I want to now create let's say this is this is already
we have written a function to create rectangle now if I want to create rectangles let me create
rectangle let me call it rectangle one so if I want to create a rectangle one then I need to call
this function create rectangle and I have to pass all these three values right so the first value
that I have to pass is the length value okay when in length I can no pass may be 10 for the width maybe
I pass no five and then no for the color I mean pass color like no blue okay now using these
you know value for the parameters which we which are right now arguments so my arguments are 10
five and blue that I pass which will be taken as param value for this parameter length width and
color so it will be masked in the order in which I have given okay so what it assumes is that the
length value that I want to pass is 10 so you know it assigns this 10 to this length and not to the
width okay so this is why we say that you know order matters okay so when you so the and these are
no positional arguments okay so in positional argument order matters and you have to give you
have to pass arguments in in the correct order then only a minute can you know print for you
this statement where you know the past argument you see is the length and second argument is the width
so if you pass no 10 and five what you can expect is 10 followed by five and the idea whatever
you want to print okay so this is what is very important so now if let's say we want to run this
so what will you expect so you you will expect a you know statement like this right
we are length and width are replaced by 10 and five and the idea is replaced by the value
no 50 right so now let's just run it and try to see whether we get what we expect if we
you
okay so let me know create another rectangle before we print the value so let me know create another
rectangle which is maybe rectangle just not by flipping these things into
okay so this is okay so I so this is the second rectangle that we created and you see I mean
I have just changed the order of you know 5 and 10 and then what we do is we print let's say
okay so whatever is you know returned we need to print it
and then followed by let me print for the other thing also when I try to print so whatever was
returned was actually stored in this variable right I mean so no that's why we were not able to
print something so it was actually or returned in this variable rectangle one and rectangle
and now we want to do is
and let me now you know print these two things and see this is what we know we expected right
so the blue rectangle it for the first call created a blue rectangle with this 10 and 5 in this
order it is no same but then you can see the order in which it has been printed length into
with okay so position actually no matters now now for many functions when you have many let's
say a lot of parameters so it's not possible always to keep in mind the order of those parameters
right so it's not always feasible to although you may recall what are the let's say input to the
functions required you may not recall the order in which these input has to be passed okay so you
may not recall the exact position of these let's say parameter so in that case there is an
alternative you know way of passing argument which is called you know keyword arguments so instead
of maintaining the order I what I say is I explicitly tell you that what this value is intended
for or no to which parameter you shall you know assign these arguments okay so this is what we
call you know keyword argument we explicitly say that you know this value should be attached to
you know this particular parameter by naming it okay for example in the same you know for the same
function if I have to let's say pass these no arguments so what we are going to do right now
is pass the same argument as keyword argument okay
so in this one you may pass in you know out of order you don't need to know you know when you
are using this keywords I mean you are telling explicitly that this particular value is for this
parameter then and the order does not matter okay so you can pass out of order so that's the
advantage of you know this keyword no arguments so you can here order does not matter okay this is
very helpful now if I want to let's say create another rectangle let's say
and this time no let's say call it rectangle 3 so in that case if I call the same let's say
what was the name of this function create rectangle and I if I don't recall what was the
you know exact order in which this argument or these parameters were defined when defining
function it no it's not a no it will not hamper my you know call okay so I can easily call without
no recalling or remembering this orders now what I say I can pass maybe the color as the first
argument okay so but here also you need to remember the
name of the parameter okay so the least that you need to remember is the name otherwise you will not
be able to call even using keyword no arguments so what I say in the color you pass may maybe you
agree okay and remember the color was not the first argument right if you see here the definition
the color was the last no parameter but I have no pass it as a no first argument okay so
but I have I'm explicitly saying that no pass in color the value green python knows I mean how
to execute this function it it doesn't have any ambiguity okay now you can you know whatever order
you want for the other three many for example in the width but I can say the pass the value
eight and in the length pass the value 12 okay so this this is this is a perfectly valid call of
the function okay and now if you want to maybe you know change this to so it's not only this I mean
you can no use any other order for example immediately after this if you want to create another
rectangle let's say rectangle four here what no I may want to do is to you know maybe pass the length
itself as a first thing okay why I may want to know pass the length as the first no argument
but since I have explicitly mentioned that the value in length is no whatever you want to you know
maybe you know some other value 15 and color you pass no some other color maybe now this time
yellow and then width you pass no any other value of it let's say no six
so this is also a perfectly valid no call to the function okay so this will not cause any
error and then if you just to check whether things have been passed appropriately or not what we
can do is we can print okay then maybe a triangle three no then followed by
rectangle four and if you know predict you see I mean it actually did exactly what we
intended to do right so this is very you know important and especially important if you have
not written function function yourself or you know even if you have written function yourself in
some let's say other module some other file you don't recall the exact you know order in which
the parameters were there it's better to be safe and use these keyword arguments okay and here
again I mean these dog string become very important like I mean if you have written the function
even yourself let's say and we have kept it in some other file you are working in a large project
you have opened another no Jupyter file and you want to now you know use your function you don't
recall I mean you don't need to actually open that file again so what you can do is you can simply
print help and your you know function name and if your description of the function the dog string
is but properly written there then everything will be printed for you okay and you can use those
you know parameter name to easily call your function yes so that's that's why also I mean it's
very important to write a descriptive dog string which can at least help you figure out what were the
you know arguments and what were the name of the parameters that this function was defined on
so so that I mean you can later on while passing the argument be very sure that if you use this
keyword you know these names as keyword and then pass the value the function will be executed
properly okay so good so now you can go either with this positional argument way or you can go
with this keyword argument way or you can also you know use both together okay it's perfectly
all right to you know mix and use both of this method I mean for some of the argument you can
actually use you know positional way of passing the argument and for some you can use keyword okay
for example let's say if I you know remember that the first you know if you know among you know
many of the key you know parameter if I remember the the first two where you know these parameter
then I can actually use positional argument there and later on if I forget what were the
order in which other arguments no appear I can use keyword argument for the again I mean as a
concrete example in the same you know space for the same function maybe you know we can again
call the same function to what we are saying is we can actually mix positional and keyword and
when doing this you know important thing is that whenever you mix positional argument and keyword
argument your positional argument should be in the beginning so okay so once you have you know
used any keyword argument you cannot use the positional argument and there is a no logic behind it
because you know if you can let's say remember the first two you you actually mention only the values
for the first two parameters and then start using you know keyword two but the moment you
started using keyword argument you are actually you you started playing with the order of the no
passing values and from that point on word python will only you know expect you to give keyword
argument because you have started you know you have somehow you know by passing some argument at
at the place of at the position of other argument you you tend to somehow I know confused from
that point on word python compiler or interpreter that what's what how should it interpret
a given value or what should be the corresponding no parameter for this particular argument okay
since you already disturbed it so better you give it as a keyword argument okay so I mean again
just to be you know concrete let me give you some examples so what I'm saying is that this is
so first let me show you some valid way to pass this mixed kind of argument so what we are
going to see some valid way in which we can mix this positional and keyword argument okay
and keyword argument and then keyword so keyword followed by position is not all over so
so the very first example is create maybe we can create another and maybe rectangle and then
ask we can call this function create rectangle and then let me say that no let's say I remember
that the first argument is length and second argument is let's say which so I can pass this to
and for the third onward if I don't recall exactly what was the order let's say
there were some other no argument also so and I don't recall now the order of the argument so I can
maybe just say argument after this point to be by just no calling the name
okay so this is a valid you know call so we can do it okay so so in this case I mean since
only one you know one of the argument was remaining it was not very beneficial but let's let me
you know copy page this to give you a more let me say that if someone only recalls that the first
argument was no length and then onward he doesn't remember whether the second argument was width
or color so in that case what he can do is you know he can say if he is confused he may want to
say that no color is maybe you know purple but I I don't know whether color and width come before
or another so in that case he can clearly maybe pass this so this is perfectly allowed okay
so why this is allowed because because in this case what so the moment I started using keyword
argument after that I'm not using you know positional argument so I can't simply you know pass seven
here so what I'm saying is this is not possible okay because you have already used the second
position to pass you know parameter which was not placed at the no seconds position so from
this point onward Python will be confused so Python will expect you to give exact keyword name
and then followed by the value okay so so the what I you know say this is not allowed so this is
no invalid but if you give no this parameter name and then pass this value seven this is perfect
for Python okay so there is no no issue okay so if we run this piece of what you will see that
no both of them run without an error okay but we can also know create some you know invalid
argument the the way I said I mean if you let me say so what I'm saying is I mean once you have
started using the keyword argument you cannot go back to the positional argument it's what we are
claiming here so for example lectave angle seven I created in the very first argument I use
that skewered argument so after this point Python is confused I mean Python expect you to give
you know all other argument also as you know keyword argument so you cannot give here you know five
and this blue even though I mean no they're incorrect order but this is not something expected by
Python so if you know do this if you run see in positional argument follows keyword argument okay
so that's the problem that you have initially given the first argument itself as a keyword
argument and then you are trying to give other argument as positional argument so which is not
what is expected no by Python okay so skip these things in mind and now we'll continue the
discussion of function again in the next video so for this video we'll conclude the lecture here
okay so I'll see you in the next video till then goodbye